### SANKET SHIRISH VILEKAR

sanket.vilekar@gmail.com | New Panvel, Sector- 5, Navi Mumbai, 410206











**CAREER OBJECTIVE**: Network Professional with 5+ years of experience specializing in Routing, Switching and Security domain. Looking forward to an opportunity in an organization to utilize my skills and abilities to develop myself as a professional and permits scope for advancement.

**CERTIFICATIONS:** Fortinet NSE 4 Network Security Professional (Verification Number: RfgEK24GB3)

Fortinet NSE 3 Network Security Associate (Verification Number: sVEyVzaOO9)
Fortinet NSE 2 Network Security Associate (Verification Number: PMaigFsaYH)
Fortinet NSE 1 Network Security Associate (Verification Number: m4vbjQcXM6)
Cisco CCNP Enterprise Training from Udemy (Cisco ID: CSCO13193234)
Juniper Networks Certified Internet Associate (Juniper ID: JPR00288975)

Cisco Certified Network Associate Security (Verification Number: DZBN5GXFKDF41E9P)

Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (Verification Number: YTCH0DHHCD11QY3P)

January 2023 December 2022 July 2021 July 2021 April 2020 December 2019 May 2019

**July 2017** 

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

## Network Security Engineer- Globesecure Technologies Limited, India (Payroll- Globesecure Technologies Limited)

**November 2022- Present** 

- Hands on experience in configuring various FortiGate firewalls like FortiGate-40F,60F,80F and 200F along with experience in Forti-Manager and Forti-Analyzer.
- Responsible for installing, upgrading and migrating network infrastructure (Firewall, IDS/IPS, Router, Switches etc.) at client location.
- Troubleshoot and fix high priority issues related to Router, Switches and Firewalls.
- Configuring Fortinet firewall for SDWAN Implementation for various projects like Central Bank of India, Aditya Birla Finance Ltd.
- Responsible for identifying bugs published by the OEM and upgrading the hardware deployed at customer location.
- Performed troubleshooting, diagnosing and solving hardware, software, and other issues affecting the network and device such as Routers, Switches and Security devices.
- Coordinated with vendors to resolve issues related to hardware and software operating system.
- Supported and guided L1 engineers for deployment, upgradation and troubleshooting.
- Coordinated with OEM's SE team to understand client requirement and prepare solution for clients.

### Network Operations Engineer- Sify Digital Services Limited, India (Payroll- Sify Digital Services Limited)

December 2021 - November 2022

• Experienced in configuring and troubleshooting various Routers and Switches like:

Cisco Routers- 1800, 1900, 2800, 800M, ISR- 4200, 4300 and 1100 series.

Cisco Switches-Cisco Catalyst 2960, 2960L, 2960X, 2960 Plus series and Cisco Nexus N9504, 3048TP switches.

Huawei Router- AR6100, AR150 series and Huawei Switches S5720, S5735 series and L3 Extreme 620x series Switches.

Juniper Routers- SRX340, SRX345 series and EX2300 series switch, HPMSR2003 Router & Aruba 2930F HP Switches and firewall Cisco ASA 5510, Fortinet 1000C.

- Gained experience in a network focused hands-on technical role working with IP routing protocols/technologies and platforms in large scale data center and/or WAN network environments and experience in ITSM tools and integration.
- Coordinated with global support teams in escalating and tracking high-severity problem impacts, assisted and analyzed tasks to remove future risk troubleshooting and fixing various network issues and connectivity problems within network including fault diagnosis and root cause analysis of network devices.
- Implemented changes in routing policies, maintenance of network devices such as device or code upgrades and gained good understanding of IP & Ethernet technologies including MPLS, Routing Protocols, BGP, IGP, ISIS, OSPF, VLAN, IP addressing, Mobility services running on IP MPLS network.
- Experienced on troubleshooting and implementation for L2 & L3 services using VPLS / MP-BGP, OSPF, ISIS, VRRP, LDP, RSVP-TE, Multicast, IP Core Planning and implementation for highly complex network and operated various network monitoring tools, application latency monitoring and reporting services.

# Analyst Technical Consultant- Global Cloud Xchange India Services Limited (Payroll- GCX India Services Limited)

June 2021-December 2021

- Gained knowledge by understanding customer requirements and produced a costed technical solution by consulting Senior Technical Consultant to support the service management team and understood Change Request requirements to propose a solution with accurate cost and design in line with predefined solutions and to provide monthly quality of service reports to all customers.
- Provided network design services, ensuring adherence to departmental policies and procedures, coordinated and defined network requirements (i.e., design, configure, install, etc.) to include consulting with end-users to determine the scope and objectives of proposed networking configurations.
- Configured, monitored and performed troubleshooting on various routers and switches to understand network infrastructure systems and internet technologies to gain knowledge on handling network/security support, problem management, managing network performance and proactively identifying issues before they become customer affecting and managing escalations to ensure outstanding customer service.

## Associate Network Engineer- NTT Ltd, Mumbai, India (formerly Dimension Data) (Pavroll- Sequelone Solutions Private Ltd)

August 2018 - June 2021

- Hands on experience in configuring and troubleshooting various Cisco Routers and Switches like: Routers- 1841, 1905, 1921, 1941, 2800, 841M, ISR- 4221, 4321 and 1100 series.
   Switches-Cisco Catalyst 2960, 2960L, 2960X, 2960 Plus series.
   Experience with configuring Huawei Pouters AP6100 series and Switches \$5720 series. HP Presidence with configuring Huawei Pouters AP6100 series and Switches \$5720 series.
- Experience with configuring Huawei Routers AR6100 series and Switches S5720 series, HP Pro-Curve Switches and firewall Cisco ASA 5510.
- 24x7 Remote Management and monitoring of Enterprise Networks of large global clients that have a distributed LAN/WAN/Wireless setup and handled customer calls and provided them with network consulting and solutions.
- Configured BGP, OSPF, Inter VLAN routing, Trunk on L2/L3 switch, static routes, PPP, Ethernet, Telnet/SSH and performed IOS upgrades on multiple vendors routers and switches like Cisco, Huawei, Juniper, HP.
- Provided escalated IT support, troubleshooting, backup and recovery, email communication and application support maintaining the 24x7 operation of the network infrastructure.

#### **EDUCATION:**

DEGREE	YEAR OF PASSING	UNIVERSITY / BOARD	PERCENTAGE
MS (Electrical Engineering) Specialization: Telecommunication and Networking	May 2017	University of South Florida, USA	GPA: 3.2/4
B.E (Electronics Engineering)	May 2014	University of Mumbai Pillai College of Engineering, Navi Mumbai, India	56.47%
H.S.C	May 2010	Maharashtra State Board	68.33%
S.S.C	June 2008	Maharashtra State Board	81.07%